星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯 前情提要
Previously on Stargate Atlantis...
母船在49小时之后就会进入
卫星的攻击范围
The hive ships will be in range
of the satellite in 49 hours.
那个卫星是唯一可以在幽灵和亚特兰蒂斯之间
起抵抗作用的东西了
That satellite is the only thing
standing between the Wraith and Atlantis.
你的意思是, 你认为它还不够强大
足以干掉一艘幽灵的母船
And you think it's powerful enough
to take out a Wraith hive ship?
根据古人的数据库, 当完全充满电时
它应该能够干掉所有这三艘母船
According to the Ancients' database, it should
be able to take out all three when fully charged.
很糟糕, 非常糟糕
This is bad. Very bad.
我不知道我能不能修好它
I'm not sure I can fix this.
幽灵的兴趣
并不在于摧毁亚特兰蒂斯
The Wraith are not interested
in destroying Atlantis.
它们到这里来是为了去地球
They're coming here to get to Earth.
这就意味着要劫持这座城市
Which means stealing the city, which
is why we have a self-destruct in place.
这也就是为什么
我们要在这里装上自毁装置
We're having trouble
docking with the satellite.
我们没法停靠到卫星上
See what you can do from your side.
没时间了
There isn't time for that.
飞到安全距离之外 再回来接我
然后在卫星教训完幽灵的飞船之后
Get to a safe distance, then come get me once
the satellite has taken care of the Wraith ships.
我们干掉一艘了!
We have a kill.
没有时间了
快点离开这里!
There's no time. Just get the hell out of here!
亚特兰蒂斯, 我是McKay!
我们已经失去了卫星!
Atlantis, this is McKay. We have lost the satellite.
- 你们有没有打下更多的飞船?
- 没有, 另外两艘飞船都完好无损
Did you manage to take out any more ships? Negative. The two other hive ships are intact.
你在那儿也做不了什么了, Rodney
返回亚特兰蒂斯吧
You can't do any more out there, Rodney. Return to Atlantis.
欢迎回来, Rodney
Welcome back, Rodney.
现在是什么情况?
Where are we?
探测器显示, 母船又开始移动了
Our scanners show the hive
ships have started moving again,
虽然移动的速度非常慢
although their pace
has slowed considerably.
很显然, 你的行动得让它们考虑考虑
Obviously, you gave them
something to think about.
不管它们是两小时后到达
还是两天后到达
If they get here in two hours or two days,
这并不能改变
我们已经束手无策的现实
it
doesn't change the fact that we're out of options.
我们不能指望跟它们战斗
We can't hope to fight them.
因此希望你们两个能够有更好的主意
So, unless either of you has any more ideas...
最后一组人已经准备好撤离了
The last group is assembled and ready for evac.
很好
All right, then.
我们把这件事做完吧
Let's get this done. Ready?
自毁程序已经启动了
准备将病毒加载到古人的主机中
Self-destruct is armed. Prepare to load the virus into the Ancient mainframe.
Rodney, 拨通阿尔法站点
Rodney, dial the alpha site.
就开始拨
Dialing.
有虫洞连接进来
We've got an incoming wormhole.
接收身份验证码...
We're receiving an I.D.C.
是谁?
Who is it?
星际之门指挥官
Stargate Command.
- 你确定?
- 肯定
Are you sure? Positive.
解除防护盾
Lower the shields.
Weir博士?
Dr. Weir?
是的
Yes.
Dillard Everett上校, 美国海军陆战队
Colonel Everett, United States Marine Corps.
你应该知道...
You should know...
O'Neill将军恭贺你们, 任务完成得很好
即便是在这种极端的环境下
General O'Neill sends his compliments on a job
well done under extraordinary circumstances.
你的任务完成了
You are relieved.
长官, 我们正准备撤退
We were about to evacuate.
- 不进行战斗?
- 是的
Without a fight. Yes, sir.
这是我的命令
On my order.
撤销撤退命令
That evacuation order is rescinded.
我想你们已经启动了自毁装置
I assume you've armed the self-destruct device?
是的, 因为Weir是想告诉你...
Yes, sir, we have, but as
Dr. Weir was trying to tell you...
我要你立刻解除它
I am going to need you to disarm it immediately.
等等, 上校
我想你并没有完全了解这里的形势
Hold on a second, Colonel. I don't think you fully grasp our situation...
有三艘幽灵的飞船
正向你们这个方向飞来
You have three Wraith hive ships
bearing down on your position
而你们没有什么可以自卫
and precious little to defend yourselves with.
是这些么?
That about sum it up?
你收到了我们的消息?
You got our message.
我们收到了消息
We got your message.
现在已经减少到两艘母船了
我们成功的摧毁了一艘
It's down to two hive ships.
We managed to destroy one.
这更好
这样我的工作就更轻松了
Good for you. That should make my job a little easier.
你的工作具体是什么, 长官?
What exactly is your job, sir?
我想那对你来说应该很清楚, 少校
我们应该不惜一切代价保卫亚特兰蒂斯
I should think that would be We are going to defend Atlantis at all costs.
obvious to you by now, Major.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第20集 围攻 第二部分
Season 1 : Episode 20
The siege (part 2)
上校
Colonel.
这是O'Neill签署的
Signed by General O'Neill.
上校, 我们并不是不感激
Colonel, it's not that we don't appreciate the thought,
不过如果你读过那份介绍
舰队正朝这里开来的报告
but if you had read the report
on the armada headed this way,
我们没有什么可以做了
you'd know there's not much we can do about it.
是的, 我 一页一页的读过你们的报告
Oh, I read your report cover to cover, Major.
你们一定是找到了一个ZPM
They must have found a ZPM.
只有这样你们才能从地球拨号到这里
That's the only way they could
have dialed in from Earth.
它是被一队考古学家在埃及发现的
It was discovered in Egypt
by a group of archaeologists.
这个该死的东西一直都藏在我们眼皮底下
The damn thing has been under our noses the whole time.
难以想象！
Fantastic. Wait a minute.
等等, 你们怎样才能把那个ZPM带到这里来?
你们需要它建立虫洞
How could you possibly bring the ZPM back here? You need it to maintain the wormhole.
在我们说话的时候, 它已经被传送到了
Daedalus号上了, 我们的新战舰
As we speak, it is being transported up
to the Daedalus, our new battlecruiser.
Prometheus号的姊妹舰
我简直无法想象它已经造好了
Sister ship of the Prometheus. I didn't even know it was finished.
利用那个ZPM的能量
她将会在四天内到达这里
With the ZPM boosting her engines, she
should be here inside of of four days.
在这段时间内我们要守住这个基地
That is how long we have to hold this base.
Sheppard少校
拨通那个飞马座的阿尔法站点
Major Sheppard, dial Pegasus alpha
site, recall all military personnel.
叫所有的军事人员, 连同所有
愿意回来帮忙的平民, 马上回来
As well, any civilians who would like to return and
help take part in damage control are welcome to do so.
我们非常欢迎他们
And when you're done with that,
在你做完之后
到我设在会议室中的办公室中来
please join
me and my officers in the conference room.
我们将讨论一下我们的战术安排
We'll discuss our tactical position.
Everett上校?
Colonel Everett.
好吧, 现在你是主管
Fine, you're in charge,
不过有需要我的地方
可以去那个简报厅找我
but
I should be at that briefing.
如果涉及到亚特兰蒂斯的其它方面时
我很乐意让你加入
When it comes down to any other aspect of
Atlantis, I will be happy to include you.
我们是在谈我们的战术安排
We're talking about our tactical position.
- 我明白...
- 很好!
- I understand that...
- Good.
能不能有个人去把自毁装置关掉?
Somebody want to please turn off that self-destruct?
这幅示意图是跟据你们发给我们的信息画的
它准确么?
This schematic is based on the Can I assume it's accurate?
information we got in your message.
是的, 长官!
Yes, sir.
- 上尉, 实施方案, 阿尔法2
- 是的, 长官!
Captain, deploy plan alpha-two. Yes, sir.
军士, 阿尔法2
Sergeant, alpha-two.
如果你不介意的话, 我想问一下, 上校
实施什么方案?
If you don't mind my asking,
Colonel, deploy what exactly?
我们带来了一些轨迹枪
We brought along a few rail guns.
它们本来是为Prometheus准备的
They were originally slated  for Prometheus
在他们下一次更换装备的时候
替换他们现有的装备
to replace
their current close-in armament on her next refit.
它们可以在250英里的距离上
产生速度为5马赫速度的冲击力
They will deliver an impact
velocity of mach 5 at 250 miles.
一个标准的弹夹就支持发射一万次
A standard magazine
will hold 10,000 rounds.
自毁已经被中止了
The self-destruct has been aborted.
谢谢! 你联系了阿尔法站点么?
Thank you. Did you contact the alpha site?
是我让Sheppard先不忙
I asked major Sheppard to wait
直到我有机会跟你谈谈
until I had a chance to talk with you.
- 是么?
- 是的
- Is that a fact?
- Yes, sir.
少校? 拨通阿尔法站点!
Major, dial the alpha site.
上校, 你到这里一共只有五分钟
Colonel, you've been here all of five minutes.
而到现在为止
我已经为基地中的所有人
Now, I have been responsible for
the lives of the people on this base,
包括军人和平民
both military and civilian,
负责了几个月了
for the past several months.
我不想把这些人的生命置于危险境地
直到我知道你将准备如何保卫这个城市
I'm not about to put those lives in jeopardy until
I at least know how you intend to defend this city.
我不需要向你解释, 博士
而且我也不需要你的合作
I don't need to explain myself to you,
Doctor, and I don't need your cooperation.
不过你可能需要我...长官
But you could probably use mine. Sir.
所以, 不是有意冒犯
请回答Weir博士的问题
So with all due respect, please
answer Dr. Weir's question.
- 你这不是在威胁我吧, 少校?
- 不, 长官.
Is that a threat, Major? No, sir.
我知道你需要建立一条清晰的指令链
I understand you need to establish a clear chain
of command,
不过如果你把Weir博士排除在外
but if you cut Dr. Weir out of the loop,
你将只会疏远信赖和尊敬她的人
you'll only alienate the people whose
trust and respect she's earned,
which is everyone on the base, including me.
也就是说基地中的所有人, 包括我
Is that a fact?
请坐吧
Have a seat.
我应该参加那个会议
I should be in that meeting.
我是了解这个城市防御能力的首席专家
I am the foremost expert on the
defense capabilities of this city.
是的, 你知道
当军方参与进来之后, 科学家就只能坐在旁边
You know how it is. When military steps in,
scientists take a back seat.
直到他们需要我们
Until they need us.
- 他们认为他们不需要我们
- 是的, 他们认为不需要我们
They don't think they need us. They don't think they need us right
up
一直到他们需要我们的时刻
然后他们又需要我们
until the point that they need us.
- And then... they need us.
他们需要我们
- Then they need us.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
六个naquadah增强型的核弹头
Six naquadah-enhanced nuclear
warheads,
每颗120亿吨的当量
1,200 megatons a piece.
它们是几乎所有地雷工程师的结晶
雷达是完全探测不到的
They emit almost zero E.M. and
are otherwise invisible to radar.
一旦被部署, 它们将会被近炸引信引爆
Once deployed, they will
detonate by proximity fuse.
太空地雷?
Space mines?
是的. 我们可以利用隐身的小飞船
That's right.
把它们放置在舰队和亚特兰蒂斯之间
We'll use jumpers in stealth mode to place them
in a pattern between the armada and Atlantis.
少校, 我们希望
你可以帮助我们完成这个
Major, we were hoping you could help us with that.
好的, 不过我建议留下两个备用
Yes, but I recommend keeping a couple in reserve.
不行, 我们准备一次就搞定
Negative. We'll only get one shot at this.
我们必须考虑到这种可能性...
We'll have to consider the possibility...
我的人中有四个是飞行员
Four of my men are pilots.
Beckett正在对他们进行基因植入
Beckett is giving them the gene inoculation right now.
在这完成之后, 你要带他们去熟悉飞船
Assuming it takes, you will
familiarize them with the jumpers,
他们将会成为我们的战斗机掩护分队
and they will become our fighter screen.
同我一起
Along with me.
我有另外一个任务给你
I have another job for you.
我知道这个基地装备有一个
座椅武器平台
I understand that this base is
equipped with a chair weapons platform,
类似于我们在南极洲找到的那个
like the one we found in Antarctica.
是的, 不过我们没办法为它提供足够的能量
Yes, but we have no way of powering it. We do now.
我们知道, 我们带来了一个
二号型号的naquadah发电机
We brought a mark II naquadah generator.
我们找到办法可以将
能量输出提高6倍
We found a way to increase
the power output by 600%.
这不是永久的
It won't last nearly as long,
不过应该可以在我们需要的时候
为椅子提供足够长时间的能量
but it should
power the chair for as long as we need it to.
这听起来像是一个筹划已久的计划
This is beginning to sound like a plan.
我们知道这是一个艰巨的任务
We know this is a long shot,
不过正如我所说
but like I said,
我们所需要做的就是坚持住
直到Daedalus到达这里
all we
have to do is hold out until the Daedalus gets here,
然后我们就可以用ZPM
来启动城市的防护罩
then we can use the ZPM to power the city shield.
还有什么问题么?
Any questions?
好吧
All right, then.
现在Weir博士已经被告知了所有的计划
Now that Dr. Weir has been informed of
our plans, I would greatly appreciate it
如果你们执行我的命令
联系阿尔法站点
if you'd execute my order
我将会非常感谢
and contact the alpha site.
遵命, 长官
Yes, sir.
还有, 少校!
And Major.
这是我最后一次向你重复我的命令
This is last time I give you an order twice.
明白
Understood.
你一定是Teyla了
You must be Teyla.
你一定是Everett上校
And you are Colonel Everett.
Sheppard少校在他的报告中
对你的评价很高
Major Sheppard spoke very highly of you in his report.
当然, 最近的报告让我有一点关注
Of course, a more recent report
has me a little concerned.
你认为我可以再一次陷入
幽灵的影响之中么?
You think I may once again fall
under the influence of the Wraith?
Sheppard少校向我保证, 这不会再发生了
不过我要你不要参和进来
Major Sheppard assures me that won't happen,
but I do need you to stay out of the way.
你不是需要每个有能力的人
来保护亚特兰蒂斯么?
Do you not need every able
body to help defend Atlantis?
我认为我们就可以应付
I think we can handle it.
他根本就没有试
He's not even trying.
我们已经试了几十次了
We've tried this a dozen times.
当时不是用的这个能源
But never with this power source.
我是认真的! Sheppard少校是你要找的人
I'm serious. Major Sheppard's your man.
他当然是, 不过他在训练飞行员
而现在正在部署太空地雷
Of course he is, but he's training pilots
and deploying space mines right now,
所以我们就要缠住你
so we're stuck with you.
现在, 仔细听我说
Now, listen to me very carefully,
do exactly what I tell you to do,
完全按照我所说的去做
希望没有人会受伤
and hopefully no one will get hurt.
Rodney, 一定还有其他人
Rodney, there must be someone else.
集中精力, 想着让椅子启动
Concentrate on powering up the chair.
排除其他一切杂念
Nothing else, nothing more, nothing but.
不要想着...
Don't start thinking...
不要跟我说那些, 不要开始想
或者我会开始想它!
don't tell me what not to start thinking
about, or I'll start thinking about it.
请把它启动
Please power it up.
好, 好, 好
Good. Good... good.
噢, 不
And... oh, no.
什么? 我做错什么了?
What? Did I do something wrong?
完了吧? 没什么可担心的
So... see? Nothing to worry about.
让他从椅子上下来
Get him out of the chair.
Elizabeth!
Elizabeth.
抱歉, 我已经接上了那个发电机
而且座椅平台也可以工作了
Excuse me. I've hooked up the generator, and
the chair platform is operational.
这是个好消息!
That's good news.
并不完全是
Not so much.
为什么, 有什么问题?
Why? What's wrong?
椅子只有为数不多的飞弹了
We're down to just a few dozen drones.
你直到现在才发现这个?
And you're just finding this out now?
在椅子初始化之前, 没有办法知道这个
There was no way of determining
that until the chair was initialized,
所以只有在二号发电机接上后
我才有可能发现
and that was only possible
once the mark II was tied in.
在南极洲的椅子控制了
成千上万个这种该死的东西
The chair in Antarctica controlled
thousands of the damn things.
是的, 我知道!
Yes. I know.
它们可能在古人第一次防御幽灵进攻
的时候被用掉了
They were probably used defending Atlantis the
first time the Wraith attacked the Ancients.
即使只有几十个也能帮我们
防守一会儿航空港
Even a few dozen will help us
keep them at bay for a while.
怎么了?
What is it?
有入侵者
我不知道他们来自哪里
We have incoming. I don't know where they came from.
它们是突然出现的
They just appeared all of a sudden.
怎么了?
What's going on?
我们刚刚探测到有一波目标
正在接近我们星球
We've just detected a wave of
objects approaching the planet.
有多少?
How many?
几百个
A hundred plus.
它们为什么没有被远程探测器检测到?
How come they weren't detected
by the long-range sensors?
因为它们是石头!
Because they're rocks...
小行星!
asteroids.
幽灵一定是从小行星带捕获它们
The Wraith must have harvested them
from this system's asteroid belt
然后在安全的距离之外
将它们加速抛向我们
and accelerated them towards
us from a safe distance.
主机花了很长时间才判断出
它们是一个威胁
The mainframe's taken this long
to determine they were a threat.
它们可以造成很大的破坏么?
Can they do much damage?
大部分会在大气层中烧掉
Oh, yeah, even if most of them
burn off in the atmosphere,
不过这肯定不是它们的目的
but that's not why they're doing it.
它们正冲着地雷而去
They're headed toward the mines.
它们可以被关掉么?
Well, can they be deactivated?
不行!
No.
好了
Well...
这下好了
that's that.
你的地雷炸得可真响啊, 上校
Your mines made one hell of a bang, Colonel.
我相信幽灵的耳朵还在嗡嗡响呢
I'm sure the Wraiths' ears are ringing.
怎么看不见母船的状态了?
What's the status of the hive ships?
没办法知道了
There's no way of knowing.
地雷的爆炸一定是让探测器过载了
The mine detonations must
have overloaded the sensors.
后备探测器要多久才能工作?
How long till they're back up?
那里有太多的残余辐射了
There's a lot of residual radiation.
我们在几小时之内将什么都看不到
It'll keep us blind for hours.
是的, 它们还在那里
而且我们刚刚失去了我们的首要防线
Yeah, well, they're still out there, and
we just lost our primary line of defense.
你想见我, 上校?
You wanted to see me, Colonel?
我被告知可以在这个房间里
学到很多亚特兰蒂斯的历史
I was told I could learn a lot about
the history of Atlantis in this room.
我们并没有怎么用它
因为它的能量需求太高了
We haven't used it much because
of the power requirements.
不过, 我还是想亲自看看
Still, I would like to see for myself
古人第一次是怎么失败的
how the Ancients lost the first time,
这样可以尽量避免它们所犯的的错误
try to avoid their mistakes.
是的, 长官
我们可以做到
Yes, sir, we could do that.
这是飞马星系的状态
This is the status of the Pegasus galaxy
在古人遭遇到幽灵之前
before the Ancients encountered the Wraith.
蓝色的代表有古人居住
或者受到古人保护的星球
The blue stars represent systems either
inhabited by or protected by the Ancients.
然后...
Then...
这是他们战斗了大概一百年后的样子
this is how it looked after
they fought for almost a hundred years.
所有这些当中, 只剩下亚特兰蒂斯了
Until Atlantis was all that was left?
是的
Yes, sir.
这就是围攻开始的时候
That's when the siege began.
在接下来的几年中
亚特兰蒂斯还可以抵御入侵者
For several more years, the Atlantians
were able to hold off their attackers,
依靠城市的防护罩和更先进的武器系统
relying on the city's shield and superior weaponry,
包括卫星武器系统
including the weapons satellite system.
但是不管摧毁了多少艘幽灵的飞船
总是会有更多的飞船不停地赶来
No matter how many Wraith ships They could win almost every battle,
它们可以打赢每一场战斗
but they saw no way to win the war.  they destroyed, more kept coming here.
但是他们发觉无法赢得这场战争 于是, 他们沉下城市然后离开了
So... they submerged the city... and left.
就这些?
That's it.
这是传说
That's the story.
不过图景非常清楚
But the picture is pretty clear.
所以你认为这是一场打不赢的战争
So you think this is a no-win situation?
不, 长官
我的意思是
No, sir. What I mean is,
即便是我们在这一次打败了它们
它们还是会回来
even if we beat
them this time, they're going to come back.
少校
Major...
我想我可以告诉你
I think I should tell you
Marshal Sumner上校
是我的一个非常要好的朋友
that colonel
Marshall Sumner was a very good friend of mine.
我们一起共事多年
We served together a lot of years and
你知道...
you know...
我不能只为自己活着
I cannot, for the life of me,
很想知道为什么你已经走了那么远
却仍然没有救他
figure how it is that you could go
as far as you did and not save him.
你怎么能够离得那么近却...
- How you could get that close...
在我找到Sumner上校的时候...
- By the time I reached colonel Sumner...
更糟! 你向他开枪杀了他
worse, you admit to firing
the shot that killed him.
因为我相信这是他要我做的
Because I believe that's
what he wanted me to do.
你很了解他, 是么?
You knew him that well, did you?
你当时不在那里, 长官
You weren't there, sir.
我喜欢是为他好
I wish, for his sake, I was.
那晚的情景总在我脑中挥之不去
There isn't a night that doesn't go by
where
当时的情景总在我眼前重演
that moment doesn't play in my head...
每当那个时候...
and every time it does...
控制室
Control room...
我是Everett上校, 请回话
This is colonel Everett. Report.
长官, 我们刚刚探测到
一波梭镖飞船入侵
Sir, we've just detected a wave of darts inbound.
我就来
到椅子那儿去
I'm on my way. Head to the chair.
这事我们以后再说
We'll finish this later.
发生什么了?
What's happening?
很多个信号, 长官
正在飞快地接近中
Multiple signals, sir, closing fast.
McKay说得没错
核爆炸损坏了探测器
Dr. McKay must've been right about
the nukes damaging the sensors.
直到它们飞到我们头顶上时
我们才发现
We couldn't see them until
they were right on top of us.
射击手就位了么?
Are my gunners in position?
是的, 长官
Yes, sir.
损害控制分队呢?
About our damage control parties?
他们都已经就位了
They're all in position.
很好, 关闭城市的灯光
All right. Darken the city.
记住! 短, 稳, 快
Remember, short steady bursts.
它们来了
Here they come!
McKay, 把它开动起来
McKay, fire it up!
要等一分钟
It'll take a minute.
我们一分钟也不能耽误了!
We don't have a minute.
这个发电机只有在工作于一个
近似过载的边缘状态时
This generator can only power the chair
才能为椅子提供能量
because it
operates in a state of barely-controlled overload...
快点让这个该死的东西工作起来!
Just get the damn thing working.
这正是我在努力去做的
That's what I'm trying to do.
上校, 我是Radnor!
Colonel, it's Radner.
说吧
Go ahead.
看起来它们当中有一些
开始进行神风敢死队似的攻击
It looks like some of them are
starting to make kamikaze runs.
发生什么了?
What happened?
我们失去了主要系统
We lost primary systems.
有一个射击点停了
One of our gun positions is dark.
Farrell, 你怎么不射击了?
Ferrell, why aren't you firing?
Farrell, 回答!
Ferrell, report.
上校, 我是Ford中尉
我离Farrell的位置比较近, 我就过去!
Colonel, this is lieutenant Ford. I'm near Ferrell's position. I'm on it!
好了你有能量了, 干吧!
You've got power. Go!
城市的探测器没有能量供应了
Power is out in sections of the city.
远程探测器和内部探测器都不工作了
不过我们正在着手解决
The long-range scanners and the internal
sensors are down, but we're working on them.
我想知道那些母船的状态
I want to know the status of those hive ships A.S.A.P.
它们正在靠近, 这就是它们的状态!
They're coming. That's their status.
明天, 后天, 大后天!
Tomorrow, the day after, the day after that...
最终, 它们会到这里的
eventually, they'll get here.
我们是不是在这里欢迎它们
就是另外一回事了
Whether we're here to greet
them or not is another matter.
Rodney
Rodney.
听者, 那个椅子已经用完弹药了
你准备怎样应付下一波?
Look, the chair is out of drones. How do you expect to handle the next wave?
我接受大家的意见
I'm open to suggestions.
真的么?
Really?
我们去攻击母船
We target the hive ships.
用什么?
With what?
我们驾驶处于隐形状态的小飞船
直取它们的咽喉
We fly the puddle jumper in stealth
mode right down their throats.
你是准备完成一项自杀任务?
Are you volunteering for a suicide mission?
这不会是一次自杀任务
It won't be a suicide mission if McKay and Zelenka
如果McKay和Zelenka找到了
可以远程控制小飞船的办法的话
can figure out a way to remote-control the jumpers.
你能做到么?
Can you do it?
- 据我所知, 这是有可能的
- 是真的么?
I knew this was going to happen. Is that a fact?
是的, 是真的!
Yes, it's a fact.
你带着你的枪和士兵出现在这里
Look, you show up here
with your guns and your brush cuts,
不过要真正拯救这个城市的时候
你却转向科学家求助!
but when it comes to actually saving the city,
而且每次你的要求都是不可能的
you turn to the scientists, and
every time, what you ask is impossible.
你上次睡觉时在什么时候, 博士?
When was the last time you slept, Doctor?
住嘴, 我有主意了
Shut up. I have an idea.
- 那个椅子
- 当然, 那个椅子
The chair. Of course, the chair.
问题是, 怎么把它接入飞船系统
The problem is tying it
to the jumper's systems.
同时不让发电机过载
Without overloading the generators.
可能可以使用小飞船自己的飞弹
作为一种推进的方法
Possibly using the drones on the
jumpers themselves as a means of propulsion...
同时将惯性阻尼器增加到最大
while increasing the inertial dampening to maximum.
操作起来可能比较困难
不过确实是可能的
It won't be very maneuverable,
but possibly, possibly...
- 有可能
- 那就是说可以了?
Is that a "yes?"
不, 只是有可能
No, it's a "possibly."
我会认为是!
一艘飞船可以造成多大的损坏?
I'll take it. How much damage
can one puddle jumper do?
我也有个主意
我想我知道我们可以去哪里再弄一个核弹
I've got an idea about that, too. I think I know where
we can get another nuke.
少校, 我不知道Genii
对我们处境会有多大的同情心
Major, I don't know how sympathetic
the Genii will be to our situation.
Genii?
The Genii?
他们不是想测试他们的武器么?
现在机会来了
They want to test their weapon. Now's your chance.
让我过去!
Let me pass!
我要跟Weir博士说话!
I need to talk to Dr. Weir!
Teyla?
怎么了?
What's the matter?
幽灵
他们已经进入亚特兰蒂斯了!
The Wraith... they are in Atlantis.
幽灵飞行员进行自杀式飞行
The Wraith piloting the kamikaze ships
beam into the city right before they hit.
在撞向城市之前, 通过光柱潜入进来
So they're trying to take the city intact.
这就是说它们试图完整无缺的夺下城市
它们到底有多少?
How many are we talking about?
有多少梭镖飞船坠毁了?
How many darts crashed?
大概20到30之间
内部传感器仍然不能工作
Between 20 and 30,
and internal sensors are still down.
好吧, 我们有这个
Well, we have this.
这个不能区分任何幽灵
It can't differentiate between Wraith and human,
不过如果我们将基地中所有的人
限制在一个特定的区域
but if we confine all base
personnel to the designated areas,
那么这里显示的区域之外的小点
就很有可能是目标
the blips that show up out
of bounds will be the likely targets.
让我看看
Let me see that.
对你没有任何用, 你需要特定的基因
It won't do you any good. You need the gene.
我也接受了基因治疗
I got the gene therapy, too.
我们希望能提供帮助
We wish to help.
这是一个很大的城市, 上校
This is quite a large city,
你需要尽可能多的人开展搜索工作
you need
as many people searching as possible.
她是能第一个感觉到幽灵存在的人
She is the one who sensed the
Wraith presence in the first place.
上尉?
Captain.
给这些人一些武器
Get some weapons for these people.
是的, 长官
Yes, sir.
在这个基地中, 还有其他人
拥有古人的基因
There's other people on this base that possess
the Ancient gene...
例如, Kusanagi博士
我相信她一定愿意帮助的
Dr. Kusanagi, for example. I'm sure she'd relish the opportunity to help.
是的! 我现在又累又饿, 坐下去!
Carson, 它已经没有飞弹了
I am exhausted and starving, so sit down. Carson, it's out of drones.
你做不了任何破坏,  即便是你想的话
You couldn't do any damage if you wanted to.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了, 我们开始做事
下到航空港去, 到了之后用无线电通知我!
Okay, we're in business. Radio me when you get there.
Head down to the jumper bay.
你还好吧?
You okay?
下一次, 你去当诱饵怎么样?
How about next time you can be the bait?
下一次, 也许吧
好了, 这边!
Yeah, maybe. Next time. Okay, this way.
我们刚刚收到Genii的回复
We just received the response from the Genii.
我们听听吧
Let's hear it.
我是Genii人Prenom
我们很欢迎我们两个民族之间能够开展对话
This is Prenum of the Genii. We welcome the opportunity to
open a dialogue between our two people.
你们排个代表过来
一个人, 不许带武器
Send your representative... one person, unarmed.
- 就是这些?
- 是的, 女士
Is that all? Yes, ma'am.
Everett上校, 我是Weir
Colonel Everett, this is Weir.
正如我们所希望的
Genii要求我们派去一个代表
As we'd hoped, the Genii have
asked us to send a representative.
我准备过去
I'm set to go.
好, 我找不出比你更有资格的人了
Good. I can't imagine anyone more qualified.
如果你搞定的话, 我会请你喝一杯的
Pull this off, and I'll buy you a drink.
就这样
拨通星际之门
You've got a deal. Dial the gate.
Weir博士, 我是Prenom
Dr. Weir... I am Prenum of the Genii.
我非常惊奇, 不, 是震惊
你竟然有胆量到这里来
I'm rather surprised... no, astonished that
you would have the audacity to come here.
你已经收到我们的消息了
幽灵就在我们门口了
You heard our message. The Wraith are at our doorstep.
可以想象, 对你们濒临灭亡的处境
我们感到十分的欣喜
And we are understandably delighted
at the prospect of your demise.
可能是这样吧
不过, 我们有你们想要的东西
That may be so... but, still, we have something that you want.
C4
C-4.
不仅仅是那个, 我们有机会替你们
测试你们的武器, 而不用担心会伤到你们
More than that. We have an opportunity for you to test your weapon
而且还有可能打败幽灵
at no risk to yourselves,
and a chance to strike at the Wraith.
你无法想象它们已经离得多进了
You have no idea how close they are.
幽灵曾经来过, 博士
The Wraith have come, Doctor.
六天以前
Six days ago.
幸运的是, 我们提前探测到了它们
并且及时关闭了我们的反应堆
Fortunately, we detected their approach and we were able to shut down our reactors in time.
在地面上, 我们失去了好几百人
Hundreds of lives were lost on the surface,
不过还是有数千人获救了
因为我们在地下的设施没有被发现
but thousands more were saved because
our underground complex went undetected.
因此你应该知道, 对Genii的威胁
已经到来了而且已经过去了
So, you see, the threat to the Genii has come and gone.
只要幽灵没有注意
它们不再会对这个星球感兴趣了
So far as the Wraith are concerned, this planet is no longer of interest to them.
我们有McKay博士提供给我们的设计图
We have the design that Dr. McKay provided for us,
现在我们的原型核弹已经接近完成了
and our prototype bombs are nearly complete.
那你为什么要我到这里来?
So why would you ask me to come here?
这样我们就可以用你的命
来交换C4
So that we may trade the C-4... for your life.
该死!
Damn it.
我是Everett
幽灵刚刚破坏了我们的一个发电机
This is Everett. The Wraith just took out one of our generators.
最近的发电机站是哪个?
三号!
What's the nearest generator station? Number three,
Teyla的队伍更近!
but Teyla's group is closer.
Teyla?
我们已经在路上了, 少校!
We are already on our way, Major.
我已经给你们C4了
I have already offered you the C-4.
你现在想要我们的武器原型进行交换
And you want our prototype weapons in exchange.
这种交易对Genii来说不公平
That's not a bargain for the Genii.
如果你现在有C4的话, 你会怎么做?
What would you do if you had the C-4 right now?
把它结合到你们的武器中去?
Incorporate it into your weapons?
- 是的
- 那么你需要测试他们!
Yes. And you would test them.
当然
Of course.
我正提供给你机会
可以在幽灵的母船上测试你的武器
I am offering you the chance to test
your weapon design on a Wraith hive ship,
而且绝不会伤害到你的人民
at no risk to your own people,
而且你们仍然还可以制造更多
and still have enough to build dozens more.
现在, 你要么是太自傲, 要么是太愚蠢
以至于不能看到...
Now, if you are too proud or too stupid to see...
说话小心点, 博士!
Be careful, Doctor.
我现在顾不上了!
I am way past careful.
现在你知道我们的协议
Now, you know what the deal is,
是接受还是拒绝, 由你吧
and it's a damn good one, so take it or leave it.
好了, 就是这了!
Yeah. That's it.
OK, 测试一下
Okay... let's give it a test.
准备
Standing by.
Carson? 我需要你清除所有杂念
只想着小飞船
Carson, I need you to clear your mind and think about the puddle jumper.
想着让它启动起来
Think about bringing it online.
快点, 快点, 快点
Come on, come on, come on...
现在就启动吧
any time now.
Carson
Carson...
我知道你可以做到
启动小飞船
look, I know you can do this. Just activate the puddle jumper.
好, 好, 好, 好
Rodney, Rodney, 起作用了
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Rodney, Rodney, it works!
给我个无线电
Give me your radio.
我是Weir
This is Weir.
我已经拿到原型核弹了
I've got the prototypes.
原型核弹, 好
Prototypes. Right.
这应该是最后几个了
That should be the last of them.
上校?
Colonel.
做得好, 博士
我必须承认, 我深受感动
Well done, Doctor. I...I have to admit it, I am impressed.
好吧, 也许对我来说, 仍然还有希望
Well, maybe there's hope for me yet.
我坐在你的位子上了
I'm in your chair.
我认为那是你的位子
I thought it was your chair.
好吧, 是的, 我不是经常要坐
Yeah, well, I... I don't sit much.
我要去检查...
I was just going over the...
我们有个麻烦
We have a problem.
我们有很多麻烦
We have a lot of problems.
我刚刚检查完Genii的核装置
它们没有完成
I just finished examining the Genii nuclear devices. They're incomplete.
我可以完成, 不过这需要时间
I could finish it, but it's going to take time.
要多长时间?
How much time?
差不多一天
About a day.
我们没有一天的时间了, 博士
We don't have a day, Doctor.
正如我所说的, 我们有个麻烦
Well, like I said, we have a problem.
你要见我, Rodney?
You wanted to see me, Rodney?
是的, 是的
我需要有东西让我保持清醒
Yes. I need something to keep me awake.
是的, 我也是
Yeah, me too.
我已经为你做过事了
I've already given you something.
好吧, 我们在这里是在造一个核弹
保持清醒是先决条件
We're building nuclear bombs. Staying awake is sort of a prerequisite. Snappy.
爽快. 好吧, 我会再给你打一针兴奋剂
坚持住!
All right, I'll get you another stimulant. Carry on.
谢谢
Thank you.
对你的一些人民, 我感到非常抱歉
I'm sorry you lost some of your people.
死了很多人, 上校
Many have died, Colonel.
我是四号飞船
我们已经看到幽灵的母船了
This is jumper four. We have a visual on the hive ships.
我是Everett
This is Everett.
四号飞船刚刚报告
幽灵的母船已经逼近这个行星了
Jumper four has just informed us
the Wraith hive ships are approaching the planet.
防御队伍, 各就各位
Defense team, to your positions.
博士?
Doctor?
谢谢
Thank you.
我是Weir
This is Weir.
我知道你们现在都已经很疲惫了
Now, I know how tired you all are,
在过去几天里
让你们去做的事太多了
and how much we have asked of you these past few days.
值得乐观的是
Daedalus号马上就会到了
Hopefully, the Daedalus will arrive soon,
不过在那之前
我们的命运仍然掌握在我们自己手中
but until that happens,
our fate is in our own hands.
如果在这场战斗中
我们的任务失败了
If, during the course of
this battle, that mission fails,
我会下达撤退的命令
I will give the order to evacuate.
现在我们希望那不会发生
Now, we all hope it won't come to that,
但如果确实发生了, 不要犹豫
but if it does... don't hesitate.
就是这些
That is all.
没时间了
Time's up.
好, 正好, 我们也完成了
Oh, what a coincidence. We're done.
那么, 去椅子所在的房间吧
Oh... so... chair room?
好吧
Right.
上校, 我们准备去航空港
给小飞船装上核弹
Colonel. We're heading into the bay to load up the jumpers.
知道了
Understood.
记住, 我欠你一杯
Remember... I owe you that drink.
慢点, 慢点, 慢点
就在这里
Slow. Slow, slow, slow. Right here.
Sheppard, 你准备好了么?
Sheppard, are you ready?
Rodney?
发电机能量输出不太正常
The generator's not powering up like it should be.
它们又发起了一波进攻
少校, 我们需要立刻开始!
They're sending in another wave! Major, we need to go!
McKay!
有地方不对劲!
能量级别正在下降!
There's something wrong.
Power levels are dropping!
Rodney, 还是没有动静!
Rodney, nothing is happening.
为什么没有小飞船升空?
Why are there no jumpers in the air?
我们一定是用光了二号发电机的能量
它已经死了!
We must have exhausted the mark II's energy output. It's dead!
太久了, Rodney
So long, Rodney.
应该有办法来...少校!
There's got to be a way to... Major!
到上面去, 它们已经在基地中了
Heads up, people! They're in the base.
上校, 我们有麻烦了
Colonel, we have a problem.
是什么?
What is it?
我们可能需要下令撤退了
We may need to give the order to evacuate.
Elizabeth, 等等!
Elizabeth, wait!
你不能!
You can't.
我必须这样去做, 你是知道的
I have to, and you know it.
John?
John...
去吧
Go.
该死的小飞船到底是怎么了
What's the status on that damn jumper?
已经在路上了
It's on its way.
Weir博士
Sheppard少校已经驾驶着小飞船出去了
Dr. Weir, major Sheppard is taking the jumper out.
我知道了, Zelenka博士
开始准备二号飞船
I'm aware of that, Dr. Zelenka. Start prepping jumper two.
Teyla, 我听到了枪声
你那边情况怎么样?
Teyla, I'm hearing gunfire. What's your status?
Teyla, 你能听到么?
Teyla, do you hear me?
Teyla!
Teyla?
希望我引爆这一个之后
就用不上另外一个了
Hopefully, if I take this one out, the other one will back off.
走, 走, 走!
Go, go, go, go!
我们不能呆在这里了, Elizabeth
We can't stay here, Elizabeth.
他是对的
它们正通过光柱从四处近来
He's right, they're beaming in all over the place.
我们哪儿也不去
还没到那步
We're not going anywhere. Not yet.
你知道, 如果这有效的话
可能需要有人再做一次
You know, if this works, somebody might have to do it again.
知道
Understood.
快, 快!
Come on. Keep up!
在那里!
Over there.
是你让Sheppard驾驶那个飞船的?
You let Sheppard fly that jumper?
帮我准备好自毁程序
万一这失败的话
Help me arm the self-destruct in case this fails.
它们没有察觉到我的靠近
They haven't detected my approach.
核弹已经准备好了
The weapon is armed and ready.
我就要进去了
I'm going in.
未完待续...